## Clayton W. Seitz, PhD

#### cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I specialize in the development and application of machine learning methods for computer vision, large language models, time series analysis, and generative modeling. I maintain a strong background in functional and object-oriented programming with experience writing production quality software.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Doctor of Philosopy, Physics

2024

Purdue University

## Master of Science, Physics

2021

University of Chicago

# Bachelor of Science, Physics, Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University
Minor: Mathematics

# Bachelor of Science, Informatics (Math Focus), Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Graduate Researcher

2022-Present

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

- Designed diffusion models/score-based generative models and general computer vision techniques (object detection, segmentation, etc.) in PyTorch for modeling image datasets in super-resolution fluorescence microscopy
- Developed general probabilistic models for high-dimensional imaging datasets and associated Bayesian methods for statistical inference tasks
- Developed novel hardware systems for super-resolution imaging of human cells

#### Graduate Researcher

2020 - 2022

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

- Investigated fundamental learning mechanisms in recurrent neural networks (RNNs) using dynamical models, mean-field theory, and time-series analysis.
- Designed and ran Monte Carlo simulations of spiking neural networks

#### Research Assistant

2019-2020

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

- Developed a scientific package in Python known as "cellquantifier" for highthroughput object detection and tracking
- Managed the package lifecycle and user training throughout the laboratory

#### Information Systems Intern

2016

Liberty Mutual Insurance

- Wrote Python scripts to automate attestation testing of web facing servers
- Assisted in configuration of web application firewalls (WAFs)

## AWARDS

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL 2020

Travel Award and Lightning Talk Invitation Physical Sciences in Oncology - Minneapolis, MN 2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship

2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Uncertainty-aware localization microscopy by variational diffusion. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Quantum enhanced localization microscopy with a single photon avalanche diode array. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz<sup>†</sup>, Donghong Fu<sup>†</sup>, Mengyuan Liu, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. BRD4 phosphorylation regulates the structure of chromatin nanodomains. https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.03.611057. 2024

> Maelle Locatelli<sup>†</sup>, Josh Lawrimore<sup>†</sup>, Hua Lin<sup>†</sup>, Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS 12 July 2022; 119 (29): 1-11

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International 15 January 2022; 46 (5): 683-700

> Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 25 October 2021; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. Cytokine-induced transcriptional memory is evident in the kinetics of transcriptional bursts. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2022

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

## **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

Programming Languages & Software: Linux, Bash, Python, R, PyTorch, C/C++, SQL, LaTeX, Git, Docker, SLURM, Azure, AWS